forbesmagazine.com 2018-05-14

# Privacy Policy

## FORBESMAGAZINE.COM PRIVACY POLICY

_Updated as of July 6, 2015_  
  
---  
  
### _What this Privacy Policy Covers_

This privacy policy covers the processing of a your information on [www.forbesmagazine.com](http://www.forbesmagazine.com/) (the “Website”), owned and operated by Forbes Media LLC (“Forbes”), in connection with the ordering of and subscription(s) to Forbes Magazine (the “Magazine”) and activities of the Website. Other Forbes digital sites linked to from the Website have their own privacy statements which can be viewed on those sites.

**_Gathering of Information_**

### _Voluntary Submission_

The Website does not collect personally identifiable information about any individual Website user except when knowingly and expressly provided by that individual. For example, we may ask you for information, such as your e-mail address and/or physical address when you purchase back issues or subscribe to the Magazine. You may also provide information to the Website in other contexts, including, for example, to enter into a sweepstakes or promotion. In the event you order something from the Website, a third party that we engage may collect additional personal information, such as your address, and credit card information in order to complete and process the purchase. You always have the option not to provide the information we request. If you choose not to provide the information we request, you can still visit the Website, but you may be unable to access certain options and services. When you register on or provide information on the Website in any manner, you agree to provide only true, accurate, current and complete information.

### _Cookies_

A cookie is a small data file that is written to your computer's hard drive by your web browser. A cookie file can contain information, such as a user identification code that a website will use to track the pages and number of times you have visited. Forbes uses cookies to track web analytics throughout the Website and membership status so that you don't have to login each time you visit the Website. The data read from these cookies may be linked to personally identifiable (PII) and non-personally identifiable (non-PII) information.

Business partners of Forbes, vendors providing hosting and other services for the Website and third party analytics providers may set their own unique cookies through your browser. 

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser settings to display a warning before accepting a cookie, choose to accept cookies only from certain websites or to refuse all cookies. However, if you choose to disable the receipt of cookies from the Website, you may not be able to use certain features of the site.

### _Web Beacons_

We use web beacons (invisible images often referred to as pixel tags or clear GIFs) on our sites in order to recognize users, assess traffic patterns, identify preferred content and measure site engagement. We also include web beacons in our e-mail messages, in order to count how many e-mail messages have been opened.

The Website also uses a reputable third party to collect information, including through the use of web beacons, browser cookies and other tracking technologies. We may collect via web beacons various data provided by your browser while you are on our site and elsewhere where we may be acting as a 3rd party. This data is collected in the aggregate, but may include or be associated with other non-PII or PII that users have voluntarily submitted.

### _Log Files_

Forbes’ web servers log information about a site user's IP address, browser type and the current URL the user is requesting. This information is always provided by each and every user's browser. These log files are stored in a secure location and used --in an aggregated, anonymous manner--in our internal analysis of traffic patterns within our website. This information is automatically logged by most websites.  
  
### _Use of Information_

Our primary goal in collecting user information is to enhance your experience on our website.

### _To Process Your Payment_

We use a third party vendor to process payments you make on our website for the purchase of Forbes Magazine. When you submit payment, the vendor may ask for information such as your email address, physical or mailing address and credit card number. The vendor will be prohibited from using our users' personally identifiable information for any other purpose. The vendor has verified to us that it is also Payment Card Industry compliant. For customer service related to payments or processing of your Forbes Magazine subscription, please email [frbcustserv@cdsfulfillment.com](mailto:frbcustserv@cdsfulfillment.com) or call 1-800-888-9896.  For customer service related to back issues, please email [getbackissues@forbes.com](mailto:getbackissues@forbes.com) or call 212-367-4141.

### _To Provide Communications From Third Parties_

We respect the privacy of our users and shall not disclose or distribute our user list to any third party, nor shall we permit anyone else to do so. 

### _Control of Your Information_

You may edit your account information at any time by logging in and going to “Edit Your Account Information”.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### _Sharing of Information_

When you are on an area of the Website and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Forbes as well as business partners and vendors providing hosting and other services for Forbes.

We use third parties to provide credit card processing, e-mail service providers and hosting services on our site. When you sign up for such services, we will share your personally identifiable information as necessary for the third party to provide that service. These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose. If you do not want your information to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer of your information by not using that particular service or the Website.

From time-to-time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you, such as your name and e-mail. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you have the choice whether or not to disclose this information. We use this personally identifiable information to notify contest winners and award prizes.

We may use a third party service provider to conduct these surveys or contests; that company will be prohibited from using our users' personally identifiable information for any other purpose. We will not share the personally identifiable information you provide through a contest or survey with other third parties unless we give you prior notice and choice.

### _In The Event of Sale or Bankruptcy_

The ownership of Forbes Magazine may change at some point in the future. Should that occur, we want this site to be able to maintain a relationship with you. In the event of a sale, merger, public offering, bankruptcy or other change in control of Forbes Magazine LLC and/or Forbes Magazine your information may be shared with the person or business that owns or controls this site. Opting out of receiving information from third parties will not affect our right to transfer your information to a new owner, but your choices will continue to be respected regarding the use of your information. You will be notified as described below in "How will I know if the Privacy Policy is changed."

### _As Required By Law_

Forbes may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or legal process served on Forbes or to protect and defend the rights or property of Forbes.

### _Security_

Your information is stored on Forbes’ servers located in the United States. We use industry standard procedural and technical safeguards to protect your personal information against loss or theft as well as unauthorized access and disclosure to protect your privacy, including encryption, "firewalls" and the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). We treat data as an asset that must be protected against loss and unauthorized access. We employ many different security techniques to protect such data from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the company. However, "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet.

### _Privacy of Children_

Kids under 13: Do not send any information about yourself to us--including information such as your name, address, or e-mail address. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. In the event that we learn we have collected any personal information from a child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information from our database as quickly as possible.

### _How to Contact Us_

If you have any questions regarding our privacy statement, please feel free to contact us by e-mail at  [customerservice@forbes.com](mailto:customerservice@forbes.com). We read every message submitted and try to reply promptly to everyone. Our mailing address is Forbes Media LLC, 499 Washington Blvd., Jersey City, NJ 07310.

### _How Will I Know if the Privacy Policy Is Changed?_

If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
